Hishiron! Let's get lunch.
（玉来(たまらい)）ひしろん お昼行こ
（日代(ひしろ)）狩生(かりう)さんは？
What about Kariu-san?
C-Come on, Hishiron!
（玉来）や… やだな ひしろん
お昼休みまで気づかなかったの？
It's lunch break.
How haven't you noticed yet?
今日 玲奈(れな) 休みだよ
Rena's absent today.
そうでしたか
She is? Then it's just the two of us today.
では 今日は２人きりですね
（玉来）そうだね
Yep!
〜♪
Revenge
Hishiron, ramen again?
ひしろん またラーメン？
他のも おいしいのに
There's other good stuff
on the menu here.
Like the fried rice and the rice omelets...
チャーハンとか オムライスとか
Tamarai-san, you look a little ugly today.
玉来さん 今日は
ちょっと ブサイクですね
Your eyes look weird.
目が 何だか おかしいです
どこかに ぶち当たりましたか？
Did you walk into something?
ちょ… やめて ひしろん
Stop, Hishiron! Don't be mean!
グサグサこないで
ブサイクとか おかしいとか
"Ugly"? "Weird"?
（玉来）ハア…
泣いたのバレバレな顔してるよね
It's that obvious I was crying, huh? Ugh...
やだな
（日代）
ぶつけたのではないとすると—
If you didn't bump into anything,
was it bees?
蜂ですか？
そう… なの！
Uh, yeah!
何か 寝てる間に刺されたみたいで
Guess I was stung in my sleep!
（日代）そうですか
（玉来）ん…
I see. Get well soon.
お大事に
（玉来）ひしろんはさ…
頭がよすぎることで—
Say, Hishiron...
Have you ever hurt someone or clashed
with them because you're too smart?
周りの人を
傷つけたり—
ぶつかっちゃったり
したことって—
今まであった？
人のやる気を そいじゃったり—
Made people give up,
もう 全部１人で
やればいいじゃんって—
or tell you to do everything by yourself?
Anything like that?
思われたり… とか
I don't really understand.
ちょっと よく分かりません
あ… アハッ
ごめん 変なこと聞いちゃって
Sorry, weird question.
Forget it.
忘れて
（狩生）失礼します
Excuse me.
（天津(あまつ)）玲奈！
Rena!
How's your ankle?
（天津）どうだった 足は？
病院—
You went to the hospital, right?
行ってきたんでしょ？
Here.
（部員）はいっ
Nice spike!
（部員）ナイスキー
（狩生）もう１本お願い！
（部員）はい！
One more!
Right!
（部員）玉来先輩！
Tamarai-senpai!
Get the nurse!
（部員）先生を呼んできて！
It's a sprain.
It'll take two weeks to heal.
（狩生）
捻挫で 全治２週間だそうです
そのあとは様子見ながら
動いていいって
I can exercise after that,
but with caution.
Whew.
そう なら大会には間に合うね
Then you can make the tournament!
You can come by practice until it heals.
Just to show your face.
治るまでは 顔出すだけでも
部活に来ればいいよ
みんなも安心するだろうし
They'll all be relieved.
About that...
（狩生）そのことなんですけど…
（天津）え？
（狩生）２週間も練習休んだあとに
試合なんて—
I think I'd drag the team down if I played
in a match after taking two weeks off.
他のメンバーにも迷惑かけるし
うまく動ける自信もないので—
And I don't know if
I'll be able to move right.
I think I'm just gonna retire.
もう このまま
引退しようと思います
（狩生）
みんなに よろしくお伝えください
Let the others know for me.
Bye.
では
ちょっと 玲奈！
Wait, Rena!
（玉来）
次は オムライスも食べてみなよ
You should try the rice omelet next time!
Kariu-san...
（日代）狩生さん
（玉来）あっ…
ハッ！ わ… 私
トイレ行ってくるね
I've gotta use the bathroom.
は… はい
Okay.
あ… 玲…
R...
（犬飼(いぬかい)）くっ
（朝地(あさじ)）
ちょっと アキ… ストップ！
No, Aki, stop.
What were you gonna do?
何する気だったの？
タマの前に
引きずって行って—
Drag her in front of Tama
and make her apologize.
謝らせようと…
ダメだってば
You can't!
You heard what Tama-chan said.
タマちゃんが
言ってたでしょ
She wants to stay friends with Kariu-san,
狩生さんとは
親友でいたいから—
自分で何とかするって
so she'll figure this out herself.
見守っててあげようよ
Watch over her.
（犬飼）今日１日 見守った
I've been doing that all day.
Show more patience.
（朝地）気が早いって
せっかく部活で—
She was finally smiling at practice.
笑うように
なったのに—
Now it's making her cry again.
また部活で泣いてんの
見てらんねえ
It's hard for me to watch.
ハア…
（大神(おおが)）狩生 部活行かないの？
Kariu, are you not going to practice?
I'm gonna study a bit today.
今日は ちょっと勉強する
ふ〜ん
Then since I'm not working today, maybe I
should do my homework before I go home.
んじゃ 俺も 今日は
バイトないし—
課題とか終わらせて
帰ろっかな〜
Arata, you're staying, right?
For make-up prep?
新太(あらた)も残るだろ？ 再試対策
（海崎(かいざき)）悪い
俺 今日 ちょっと用事あるんだ
Sorry, I've got somewhere to be today.
（大神）えっ なんだよ〜
Dude, what?
そんなんじゃ
来週もまた不合格だぞ
At this rate, you'll fail next week, too!
（海崎）うるせえよ
Shut up.
Bye.
じゃあな
I'm being a nosy old man and
leaving you two alone together.
（海崎）２人きりに
してやろうっていう—
オッサンの粋な計らいだっつうの
ありがた〜く 青春してな
Be grateful and enjoy your youth.
（狩生）いつまでいるのよ この男
How long is he gonna stay?!
みんな いなくなってから
帰るはずが…
I was just waiting for everyone to leave...
I don't want to be seen
dragging my foot like this!
足を引きずってるところなんて
見られたくないのに
よっ… よし！
じゃあ 私は そろそろ帰ろ…
Okay! Guess I'd better be go—
（大神）よ〜し 終わった〜
Okay! All done!
あっ 狩生も終わったの？
You finished, too?
んじゃ 一緒に帰ろっか
Then let's go home together!
（狩生）何て 間の悪いやつ！
His timing is the worst!
You go on ahead, Oga.
大神 先帰って
Why? Aren't you done, too?
えっ なんで？
狩生も もう終わったんでしょ？
（狩生）いいから！
Just go.
いや 意味分かんないんだけど
You're not making any sense.
（狩生）いいから！
Just go!
Don't try to make sense of it!
別に意味なんてないわよ
ほんと 空気 読めないんだから！
Take a hint already!
んっ！ 何それ
What? Man, you're extra grumpy today.
なんか 今日の狩生
輪をかけて感じ悪い
いつも感じ悪いみたいに言うな
Don't talk like I'm always grumpy!
（大神）ほら
だだこねてないで帰ろうね〜
Come on. Stop sulking, and let's go!
（狩生）えっ ちょっ ちょ…
やめてよ 非力なくせに！
Hey! Stop that, you wimpy...
（大神）ちょっ…
（狩生）痛っ！
（大神）あっ！ 狩生 ごめん…
（狩生）見るな！
Kariu!
Sorry, are—
Don't look!
（大神）うわっ いってえ…
Ow...
（狩生）ほっといてよ
Just leave me alone!
このっ！ あっ
Why, you...
Didn't you hear me?
（狩生）聞こえなかったの？
Why are you still here?!
いつまで そこにいんのよ！
ほっといてって言ってるの！
Just leave already!
（大神）
さすがに 泣いてる女子 置いて—
I can't just leave a crying
girl alone and go home.
帰れるわけないだろ
非力で 抱えてあげられないけど
肩くらい貸すから—
I'm too wimpy to carry you,
but I can lend you a shoulder,
下まで一緒に下りよ
and get you down the stairs.
The last thing you need is a fall.
階段でこけたら大変だよ
If I were a boy,
（狩生）私が男だったら—
こんな女 絶対 嫌だ
I'd hate girls like me.
Stupidly proud, short-tempered,
and utterly incomprehensible.
プライドばっか高くて すぐキレて
訳分かんない
ほのかも
あんな ひどいこと言われて—
I was so mean to Honoka.
もう 絶交されても
おかしくないのに
She might never speak to me again.
素直になれない
But I can't be honest
about my feelings.
I'm really starting to hate myself.
どんどん
自分のことが嫌いになってく…
（小野屋(おのや)）
いや〜 どうなんですかね
Man, I just don't know.
About what?
（夜明(よあけ)）何が？
（小野屋）何だか
被験者の知らないところで—
There's just so much happening
that the subject doesn't see.
いろいろ起こっちゃって
Even though one of the goals of ReLIFE
思春期の高校生たちと
関わらせることで—
年を重ねて鈍ってしまった感情を
刺激するのも—
is to reinvigorate emotions
that have withered with age
リライフの目的の１つなのに
by getting him involved
with adolescent kids.
Will he actually get involved?
ちゃんと
関わっていってくれますかね？
（夜明）まあ 海崎さんは
すぐにでも異変に気づくと思うけど
Well, I'm sure Kaizaki-san will notice
something's wrong soon.
But what then?
どうだろうね…
friends acting weird help
I knew it. Something's wrong.
（日代）やっぱり 何か変です
（海崎）おかしい
Weird...
What's been going on lately?
何だ 最近？ どうした？
I thought Hishiro-san and Kariu
had finally became friends,
日代さんと狩生—
やっと仲よくなったと
思ったのに—
but now even Tamarai-san's
eating lunch alone.
何だか今度は 玉来さんまで
バラバラで昼食ってるし
Kariu hasn't been going to practice.
狩生
最近 ずっと部活行ってないし—
Things don't seem right
between her and Oga, too.
大神とも何か変だし
何だ？ この妙な居心地の悪さは…
What's with this awkward atmosphere?
What's going on?
いったい何が？
What's with this company?
（海崎）何だ この会社？
Something's off.
何か変だ
先輩たち
もしかして仲悪いのか？
Do my seniors hate each other?
Kaizaki-kun...
（佐伯(さいき)）海崎君
（海崎）ハッ！
You're absolutely right,
and I'm glad you feel that way.
（佐伯）海崎君は正しいし
気持ちは うれしいんだけど—
But I want you to stay out of it.
あまり踏み込まないでほしいかな
あっ 日代さんだ
Hishiro Chizuru
It's Hishiro-san.
Let's see..."I need your advice."
えっと
“ご相談したいことがあります”
"I'm outside your place."
"Can we talk?"
Huh?
はい？
えっ！ ウソッ！ 何で!?
No way! Why?!
Scary! Too scary!
怖い 怖い 怖い 怖い
めっちゃ怖い
ちょ… ちょっと 待って 待って！
Wait, wait!
Hello.
（日代）こんにちは
どうしたの？ 急に
What brings you here?
ですから 相談したいことがあって
Like I said, I need your help.
LIME(ライム)だと 長文に
なってしまうだろうと思い—
Since it would be a little wordy for LIME,
直接がいいかな と…
I figured in person was better.
そんなん 電話すりゃよかったのに
You could have just called.
I've never had a long
phone call with a friend.
友達と長電話などという経験がなく
その発想はありませんでした
It never even occurred to me.
まあ… じゃあ どうぞ 上がって
Well, uh, come on in.
（日代）はい お邪魔します
Okay, thank you.
You live alone?
（日代）お１人暮らし… ですか？
（海崎）うん まあね
Well, yeah.
Oh, sit anywhere.
（海崎）ああ 適当に座ってて
（日代）あっ はい…
Sure.
Oh, yeah.
（海崎）そっか 高校生だもんな
She's in high school.
普通 友達ん家(ち)って
家の人がいると思うよな… ん!?
Generally when you go to a friend's house,
their family's around.
ってか 日代さん 来てみたら
男１人の部屋で動揺してるんじゃ…
Wait, is Hishiro-san freaking out
because it's just me here?
What now? Should I give her
an excuse to leave?
どうしよう…
うまく帰らせたほうがいいのか？
いや 日代さんの鈍感レベルは
大神並みだぞ
No, she's Oga-level dense.
別に気にもしないだろう
I doubt she cares at all.
Wait, I'm the one freaking out!
って 動揺してるのは
俺のほうじゃねえか！
U-Uh, here.
お… お待たせ
あ… すみません
Thanks.
Go ahead.
（日代）どうぞ
（海崎）ああ ごめん
Oh, sorry.
Don't jump her!
（海崎）お前らが
監視してるの分かってて—
How can I, with you guys watching?!
そんなことするか〜！
（小野屋）てへぺろ〜
Tee hee!
So, what's up?
（海崎）んで 相談っていうのは？
（日代）狩生さんと
玉来さんのことなんですが—
It's about Kariu-san and Tamarai-san.
It's weird.
おかしいんです
あれだけ仲のよかった
お２人が—
They were so close, and now
they won't speak to each other.
パッタリと
口もきかなくなってしまい…
I was wondering if you knew what happened.
何があったか
海崎さん ご存じないかなと
（海崎）ん… ごめん
Sorry. It's bugging me, too, but I dunno.
俺も気にはなってんだけど
知らない
I see...
そうですか
But I'm surprised you've been so perceptive.
でも 意外
日代さんが空気読むなんて
（日代）えっ？
（海崎）ちょっと前は—
It wasn't long ago that you'd have
asked them directly.
ちょっと前は 分からないことは
直接 本人に聞くって言ってたのに
But you realized you couldn't,
so you came to see me.
今回は そんな空気じゃないから
俺に相談に来たんだろ？
That's true.
本当ですね
Why did I go the long way around?
私は なぜ わざわざ遠回りを…
ああ 自分のことでは
ないからだと思います
Oh, I think it's because
it isn't my problem.
（日代）私は 感情が バカなので
いろいろと間違えます
I'm emotionally dumb,
so I make a lot of mistakes.
自分のことだったら
それでもいいんですが—
If it's just me, that's fine.
But with Kariu-san and Tamarai-san,
狩生さんと玉来さんのこと—
I can't afford to be stupid and mess up.
私が バカをして
間違えるわけにはいかないので…
ヘッ…
そんなバカバカ言わなくても…
You don't need to be so hard on yourself.
Last year, there was bullying in my class.
去年 私のクラスには
いじめがありました
It was not pleasant to see.
見ていて 気分のよいものでは
なかったので—
I had this weird sense of duty,
また この事態を治めることが—
like it was my job to stop it.
私の役目なのではないかという
妙な使命感で—
“やめなさい くだらない”と
注意しました
So I told them to stop this nonsense.
結果 いじめは さらに悪化して—
The bullying just got worse.
And the victim told me...
いじめられていた子から
言われました
"Don't do anything.
“よけいなことをしないで”
All I have to do is put up with it,
and it won't get any worse."
“自分が耐えていれば 今以上に
ひどくはならないのに”と…
You're absolutely right.
（佐伯）海崎君は正しいと思う
でも 組織の中では我慢も必要なの
But in any society,
you just need to grin and bear it.
Even if it isn't fair.
たとえ 理不尽でもね
I'm fine.
私は大丈夫だから
So, Kaizaki-kun... grow up.
だから 海崎君も—
大人になって
（日代）彼女は彼女なりに—
I think she was doing her best
小さな社会の中で
均衡を保っていたのだと思います
to maintain the balance in her little world.
But I stepped in, heeding only my emotions,
でも 私はそこへ
自分の感情だけで踏み込んで—
事態を悪化させてしまった
and made things worse.
I really regretted it.
やっぱり自分には 人の気持ちを
考えた行動ができないのだと—
I just don't know how to act while
considering other people's feelings.
ひどく後悔して…
After that, I did what she said.
I said nothing
そのあとは もう
言われたとおりに 口を出さず—
見ないようにして過ごしました
and pretended I saw nothing.
（海崎）
その子は 今どうなっているの？
What happened to her?
（日代）２年の終わりに
転校してしまいました
She changed schools after the year ended.
（海崎）そうか…
Oh.
Something similar happened to me last year.
俺も 去年 似たようなことがあって
At my last... school,
a senpai was... bullied.
前の… 学校の先輩が
嫌がらせを受けていて—
I got all fired up and tried to help.
俺は 勝手な正義感で
何とかしたくなって—
I lashed out at the people bullying her.
嫌がらせをしていた人たちに
反発した
日代さんの言うとおり—
But like you said,
先輩も 組織の中で
バランスを保っていたんだと思う
Senpai was maintaining her own balance.
And I upset that.
俺が それを崩してしまった
And your senpai?
その方は—
What happened to her?
その後 どうなったんですか？
（日代）その方は—
And your senpai...
...what happened...
その後—
...to her?
どうなったんですか？
ハア…
海崎さん…
Kaizaki-san?
What's wrong?
（日代）どうしました？
顔色が悪いようですが？
You don't look good.
大丈夫ですか？
Are you okay?
Kaizaki-san?
（日代）海崎さん？
Kaizaki-kun?
（佐伯）海崎君？
I'm sorry.
（海崎）すみません…
If...
俺が… もっと大人だったら
...I'd only been more grown-up...
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
すみません…
すみません すみません
海崎さん 私—
Kaizaki-san.
I don't know why you're apologizing.
謝られるような覚えが
ないのですが
うわあ〜 ぐわっ！
Ow!
だっ… ご ごめん ごめんなさい！
S-Sorry, I didn't mean to do that!
今ちょっと意識がなくて…
通報しないで！
Don't call the police!
I won't call the police.
通報なんかはしませんが
よかった いつもの海崎さんです
Good. You're back to normal.
About Kariu-san and Tamarai-san...
（日代）
狩生さんと玉来さんの件—
Is it best that I do nothing?
そっとしておくのが
最善なんでしょうか？
But I just don't like it.
でも 私 やっぱり嫌なんです
They were so close.
あんなに仲のよかった お２人が
別々にいるのを見るのは
I don't like seeing them apart.
Yeah. I agree.
ああ 俺もそう思う
It's hard to watch. I wanna do something.
見ていてつらいし 何とかしたい
（海崎）でも…—
But...
I'm scared.
怖い
踏み込んで いいんだろうか…
Scared of taking that step.
また壊してしまったら どうする？
What if I destroy everything again?
I wasn't supposed to be their peer in school.
本来 同級生でもないくせに—
彼らの貴重な青春を
荒らしていいはずがない
I don't have the right to upset their lives.
Then let's get revenge together.
じゃあ
一緒にリベンジしませんか？
私は いつまでも
失敗を引きずっている自分を—
I want to defeat the me
that's dragging this failure around.
倒したいんです
I don't want to forget my failure.
失敗は
忘れてはいけないと思います
でも
悪い思い出のまま引きずって—
But if I carry it with me as a bad memory,
and keep running away,
逃げ続けていたら
いつまでも変われないと思うんです
I'll never change.
失敗があったからこそ—
I think there are things
you learn to do through failing.
できるようになることも
あると思うんです
Kaizaki-san.
（日代）海崎さん
（海崎）ん？
Will you get revenge with me?
一緒にリベンジ
してくれませんか？
（日代）ファイ オー！
Fight on!
Bye!
（部員）お疲れ
We're headed home. Are you good to clean up?
（部員）
先に帰っちゃうけど 片づけ平気？
（玉来）あっ うん！ ありがとう
Y-Yeah! Thanks! You go on home.
お疲れさま
（部員）じゃあね
Bye!
（部員）あんまり無理すんなよ
（戸が閉まる音）
Don't push yourself too hard!
ハァ
（玉来）ハア…
（戸が開く音）
ひしろん!?
Hishiron?
Tamarai-san.
玉来さん
ちょっと お話しませんか？
Can we talk?
Tama-chan never showed up.
タマちゃん 来なかったけど
もう帰っちゃったのかな
Think she went home already?
Without telling us? No way.
俺たちに声もかけずに
それは ねえだろ
Huh? She's not here.
Did she really go home?
（朝地）あれ いない…
本当に帰っちゃった？
（犬飼）
こんなに散らかしたままでか？
And leave this mess behind?
Maybe she's in the clubroom?
（朝地）部室かな？
I see.
（日代）
そうでしたか 狩生さんにケガを…
Kariu-san's sprain is...
I'm sorry, Hishiron.
（玉来）ごめんね ひしろん
お昼もバラバラになっちゃって
We're all eating separately.
それは とりあえず よいのですが…
That's sort of beside the point.
最後の大会 一緒に出たいけど—
I want to play this last tournament with her.
But I caused her injury,
ケガをさせた張本人が
何て言ったらいいのか分からなくて
so I don't know what to say.
I can't bring myself to talk to her.
声もかけられなくて
あっ
アキ どこいくの？
Aki? Where are you going?
That redhead was still at school, right?
（犬飼）あの赤毛 まだいたよな
（朝地）ああ…
I'm gonna make her
listen to how Tama feels.
（犬飼）タマの思いを聞かせる
I'm allowed to do that much, right?
そのくらいの手助けは いいだろ
Hey, let go! What the hell?!
（玉来）
ちょっと放してよ！ 何なの 急に
Inukai-kun!
犬飼(いぬかい)くん 狩生 痛がってるから
You're hurting her!
（大神）犬飼君ってば
（狩生）ハッ！
Inukai-kun! Listen!
（大神）話 聞いてよ！
（玉来）こいつ—
This guy! He's taking me to Honoka...
私を ほのかのところに！
やめてよ！ 何…
Stop it!
（犬飼）こっからは静かにしてろ
From here on, keep it down.
Even your footsteps.
足音もたてるな
用があるなら 小声で話せ
If you must talk, whisper.
Okay. We'll do what you say.
（大神）分かった
言うとおりにするから
Shut up and listen.
黙って聞いてろ
The truth is...
（玉来）私 本当はね—
Honestly,
本当は—
I wasn't going to play volleyball
in high school.
高校では もう—
バレー やらない
つもりだったんだ
〜♪
NEXT EPISODE
Hishiro-san, what was that
"fight on" thing all about?
（海崎）
日代さん “ファイ オー”って何？
I learned about it when
I studied up on sports teams.
（日代）私なりに運動部のことを
調べていて 知ったんです
団結の儀式として
手を重ねて…
It's a teamwork ritual where
everyone joins hands and...
（日代）こう
（海崎）ああ…
Oh...
（日代）海崎さんも
どうぞご一緒に
Join me, if you like.
Everyone's Selfish Desires
Fight on!
（日代）ファイ オ〜！
（海崎）オ〜… オ…
On... Oh.